# **BRIAN STOROE**

Email: bstoroe@gmail.com

Phone: 253-326-7454

Web: www.linkedin.com/in/bstoroe

## INTRODUCTION

Software engineer with over 10 years of experience. History of working within teams to ensure quality using intuition and automated testing techniques. Motivated to grasp new technologies quickly, and expand testing coverage in breadth and depth. Track record of shipping products that benefit users in a timely manner.

## INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

#### Senior SDE - Skytap, September 2015 - August 2019

<u>Skytap</u> is a provider of cloud environments. I transitioned from SDET to SDE roles. Throughout that time, I focused on quality, defect analysis, and comprehensive monitoring of a complex distributed service architecture.

- Shipped customer-facing new/improved features, ensuring high quality and quick turn-around via automated tests. Included billing enhancements, import appliance, and application ACL and tag support.
- Contributed to internal process improvements for data resiliency and security. Included database and server migrations, backup overhaul, and service error/resiliency analysis.
- Developed site and service monitor that were primary discoverer of functional outage and degradation. Implemented in Python and TICK stack on k8s platform.
- Served on-call duty as outage first responder, responsible for initial triage and proper hand-off. Setup on-call plan and playbooks during phasing in.

#### Senior SDET - HTC, September 2011 - August 2015

I worked on the following projects as part of <u>HTC</u>'s Creative Labs division, focusing on cloud services, Android development, and innovative user experience.

- HTC Vive: VR Headset
  - Re-purposed Jira as test case management system.
- HTC Zoe: App for photo/video sharing and remixing
  - Automated service tests using Java/TestNG/Maven and use JSON schema validation for robust validation.
  - Reviewed peer code. Led test iterations, and owned critical services.
  - Benchmarked services. Evaluated performance test frameworks and used Chef/AWS to automate test environment.
- HTC Backup: First-party backup solution
  - Planned and developed testing from the ground up Android app used daily by millions of devices.

- Automated tests using monkeyrunner and uiautomator that was integrated into build pipeline.
- Developed test data generation tools using Android SDK.
- Gained and applied expertise in Android platform–Play Store publishing, logging, SMS/Contacts, backup framework, DDMS, etc.
- HTC Hub: First-party asset store for Android
  - Automated service tests using Java/TestNG/Maven.

# SDET - Quardev, April 2005 - September 2011

I worked on several projects to support the QA needs of Quardev's clients:

- Disney DCAT Group: Third-Party Commerce System Integration
  - Automated tests to validate integration of existing systems with new third-party commerce component.
  - Integrated new REST client, SQL scripts, and functional tests into in-house framework.
  - Added unit and functional tests to provide test coverage of legacy web services.
- Google Omaha: Common Windows Client Installer/Autoupdater
  - Shipped version 2 of product with initial install rate of 11 million and 500 million to date.
     Began process of shipping version 3 which is a complete re-write.
  - Automated and maintained regression test suite. Added features and fix bugs as needed in automation harness. Reviewed code for other testers. Granted python language readability.
  - Wrote detailed bug reports. Read and analyzed product debug logs to make solving defects easier.
  - Maintained and supported test tools used by several client testing teams.
  - Planned testing strategy of new features and owned core feature areas.
  - Managed issue assignment to test team. Tracked and drove bugs to lifecycle completion.
  - Used diverse tools in narrowing issues; including Wireshark, Sysinternals tools, and debuggers.
  - Tested product in widespread, comprehensive scenario testing. Compatibility was exercised by platform, third-party software, and networking environment.
- Microsoft Content Search Platform: AJAX-powered web site and custom server product for indexing and searching exclusive forms of offline content.
  - Introduced, measured, and analyzed code coverage metrics for client code. Supported team members with training and custom tools in this effort.
  - Investigated and detailed SOAP faults using protocol and domain knowledge.
  - Created test plans and cases as well as maintaining automation scripts.
  - Executed test suites for authentication and other server-side components in multi-platform, multi-environment scenarios.
  - Wrote test tools in C# to generate test data and exercise services under test outside the primary client.
- Microsoft Internet Communications Client: All-in-one package for web, email, photo sharing, and other rich online experiences.
  - Updated and expanded code for test automation harness used to execute queries against several middle-tier services. Maintained test cases and data for the same.
  - Performed functional, integration-level, and scenario-based testing against multiple product front-ends, evaluating user experience and comparing UI results to raw data for verification.
  - Verified event instrumentation using HTTP monitoring tools.
  - Owned work planning, test case development, and team reviews over assigned test areas.

- Microsoft Product Portal: Web site and comprehensive documentation system for several developer product suites. Testing included a personalized version of the portal as well as publishing tools.
  - Created and executed test cases to verify content publishing.
  - Audited and tested user authentication for enterprise content management applications.
  - Recommended program improvements to increase performance by using asynchronous execution to project stakeholders.
- Microsoft Developer & IT Courseware: VM-based lab sets for new products and technologies targeted for software developers and system engineers.
  - Isolated errors and failures in source code and scripts of developer courseware.
  - Communicated work progress with targeted status reports and developer-friendly defect records.
  - Inspected virtual machine configurations per project specification for new builds.
- Radialpoint Internet Security and Privacy Suite: Software providing PC security and online privacy intended for Broadband Service Providers to offer value added services to their customers.
  - Created and executed functional test cases by software component.
  - Verified compatibility with third-party applications on multiple platforms.
  - Archived and analyzed system changes made by the products setup routine.

# **TESTING SKILLS**

- Automated test design and debugging
- · Exploratory testing and test design
- Root cause analysis with domain knowledge and available tools
- Producing test cases, targeted status reports, and defect records

#### TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

Proficient: Python, HTTP, Windows
Intermediate: XML, SOAP, Win32 API

Familiar: C/C++, Linux, Java, C#/.NET, SQL

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Information Systems <u>DeVry University Federal Way</u> Graduated with Honors 2001 - 2004

Microsoft Certified Application Developer (MCAD) 2006